<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Opinion on Alex Again</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/opinion/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Opinion on Alex Again</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Athul</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 14:13:46 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/opinion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>You Can Still Bring Heels: a Long-term Minimalist Packing Guide</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/you_can_still_bring_heels_a_minimalist_packing_guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 20:48:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/you_can_still_bring_heels_a_minimalist_packing_guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I love travelling light. I also love getting dolled up when I visit a city. But so many one-bag travel blogs condemn bringing luxuries like a pair of heels or more than one dress.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Not this one!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I travelled for 2 years out of one 32 L backpack with a pair of heels and 2 dresses, while also being prepared for several months working on farmstays and homesteads. Packing one bag for such a wide range of scenarios simply requires careful planning, choice, a little sacrifice, and creativity. All without sacrificing style!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Patriotism during the Century of Humiliation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/patriotism_during_the_century_of_humiliation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 16:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/patriotism_during_the_century_of_humiliation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Right now, it is December 2025, in the midst of the second Trump administration. I live in Canada. Criticizing the USA and it’s inhabitants is as easy and as common as talking about the weather. Wearing any semblance of Stars and Stripes flags you as some kind of bigot.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am not a fan of the president, but I am also reluctant to condemn him or his supporters, and I am certainly stubbornly hopeful for the future of my home country.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modern Orientalism: </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/modern_orientalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/modern_orientalism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure &gt;&#xA;&#xA;  &#xA;&#xA;    &lt;img class=&#34;rounded&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2025/11/modernorientalism.jpg&#34;&#xA;        &#xA;          alt=&#34;Meme on orientalism&#34;&#xA;         &#xA;    /&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A budding idea in progress&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Weebs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yogi influencers popping up everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I myself am perilously entangled at the intersection of the „East/West“ collide as someone who is obviously of Eastern descent, yet was raised entirely in the West. I’m „2nd gen“, meaning I was the second generation born in „The New World“; my grandparents were the last generation raised in „The Old World“.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Growing up, kids and adults alike often treated me differently. Subtly, such as when I was gifted pretty chopsticks, or when everyone looked expectantly at me on Multicultural Day, and less subtly when guys said they preferred Asian women and tried pick-up lines on me in Vietnamese or Japanese. I am neither of those ethnicities, and arguably I’m not even the ethnicity I was born into; when I went back to the Homeland I was immediately identified as an outsider and targeted by scam artists.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why do I blog?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/why_blog_reclaim_your_internet_experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 20:04:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/why_blog_reclaim_your_internet_experience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Isn’t keeping a blog a bit… egocentric?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I mean it could be but it doesn’t have to be. What matters is the purpose. For instance, I blog as a means to reclaim my online experience. I don’t post so much on social media because I have this space that’s completely mine- no tracking, to ads, no weird internet politics. I built this thing myself so I know exactly what’s going on behind the scenes. You can’t say that about any social media site or really anything else if you didn’t build it yourself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hot Takes : Pre-30 edition </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/hot_takes_pre-30_edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 20:51:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/hot_takes_pre-30_edition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;pets-shouldnt-be-treated-like-people&#34;&gt;Pets shouldn’t be treated like people.&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;They can still be treated respectfully, as pets, but worrying about hurting their feelings by not including them at the table, for example,  is going too far.&#xA;„This is my baby!“ No, that’s your dog.&#xA;„She’s family; don’t exclude her.“ No, that’s a cat on the table with paws that were just scratching poop in a box.&#xA;Why do people need to coddle their pets? Why not spend that energy trying to spoil your human friends?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
