<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Travel on Alex Again</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/travel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Travel on Alex Again</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Athul</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 16:34:40 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/travel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Airport Made Me Choose: Filipino or Non-Filipino?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the_airport_made_me_choose_filipino_or_non-filipino/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 22:27:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the_airport_made_me_choose_filipino_or_non-filipino/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was 22 when I first visited the Philippines. The country where my father was born, and where all of my ancestors had lived before my grandparents moved to the New World, the Land of Opportunity— the United States.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first reckoning was before I had even left the airport terminal. “FILIPINOS,” one aisle was marked with in bold capital letters. “NON-FILIPINOS,” said the other. I stood between the two as the other passengers filed past me, confidently choosing the line they belonged in. Of course this was about what kind of passport I held, but in my sleep-deprived state it seemed like a question that rocked my very essence. My American passport suddenly felt foreign to me, despite it being my constant companion for the last several years. It named my origin, but could I claim it? After a halted breath, I chose the “Non-Filipino” line, and with each step forward, I felt the weight of that choice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You Can Still Bring Heels: a Long-term Minimalist Packing Guide</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/you_can_still_bring_heels_a_minimalist_packing_guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 20:48:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/you_can_still_bring_heels_a_minimalist_packing_guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I love travelling light. I also love getting dolled up when I visit a city. But so many one-bag travel blogs condemn bringing luxuries like a pair of heels or more than one dress.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Not this one!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I travelled for 2 years out of one 32 L backpack with a pair of heels and 2 dresses, while also being prepared for several months working on farmstays and homesteads. Packing one bag for such a wide range of scenarios simply requires careful planning, choice, a little sacrifice, and creativity. All without sacrificing style!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chasing Garbage Trucks: A Feool in Taiwan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/chasing_garbage_trucks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 18:10:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/chasing_garbage_trucks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was walking with a group of new acquaintances, locals and expats,&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Check in: Dec 14, 2025</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/check_in_dec_14_2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 15:16:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/check_in_dec_14_2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;En route to Toronto.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Somehow I forgot my coat in the middle of Canadian winter. Thankfully there are several folks at our destination that share the same sizing as me; I’ll borrow one.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Current books: Frankenstein, Roald Dahl‘s Collected Short Stories, Denial of Death&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Current jams: I Love My Computer by Ninajirachi&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What’s new this time:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;S- is old enough to have his own seat.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I brought a tablet with predownloaded movies.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;We checked a bag since we will be gone for over a month between two very different climates. I’ll exercise a more minimal approach for non-holiday travel.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A checked bag means no more carry-on; a big plus since reaching into overhead bins is difficult for my petite frame.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Having two separate seats instead of sharing one is a highly anticipated improvement that has lived up to the hype. Both of us are much happier.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lessons from Long Term Solo Travel</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/lessons_from_long_term_solo_travel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/lessons_from_long_term_solo_travel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;travel-lightly&#34;&gt;Travel lightly.&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Easier to keep track of your things if you have less things. Also, it’s easier on your back, especially if you have far to walk.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Another tip: rolling bags tend to do poorly on dirt and cobblestone roads. Sick to backpacks unless you’re going completely modern urban.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;people-are-the-same-everywhere&#34;&gt;People are the same everywhere.&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And by that I mean “people everywhere are kind, hospitable, and are more likely to take you in for a meal than steal your wallet.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Encounter at a Hostel in Tokyo</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/encounter_at_a_hostel_in_tokyo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 18:51:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/encounter_at_a_hostel_in_tokyo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is the story of how I met my husband.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;tl;dr: It was my first day at a hostel, and it was his last. We went out for beer, played Mariokart, and he left. All within 12 hours. We got married later.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;———&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sleep deprived, hungry, and strapped for cash, I stood over the stove of the hostel kitchen burning some potatoes in a pan.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I had missed my connecting flight from Singapore to Japan, so I had been up for over 36 hours figuring out how to get where I wanted to go: Tokyo. Now I was there, semi-delirious and seriously greasy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Memory of a Fellow Vagabond</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/memory_of_a_fellow_vagabond/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/memory_of_a_fellow_vagabond/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the most memorable encounters during my 2 year stint as a vagabond was another traveller at a hostel in Christchurch, New Zealand. A modern, clean place that had an indoor turf area and outdoor stainless steel fire pits. The kind of hostel that had “pods” rather than “bunks”. It smelted like an airport in there.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What was notable was what &lt;em&gt;wasn’t&lt;/em&gt; said. Usually, names are exchanged after the standard questions of “where are you from?” and “how long will you be here”, and goodbyes are peppered with hopeful phrases such as “maybe we’ll see each other again” or “let’s stay in touch. What’s your instagram?”.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
